[
    {"question":"A short, repeated musical pattern used as a structural device in music is known as a(n):",
    "ans1":"drone", "ans2":"ostinato", "ans3":"contour", "correctAns":"ostinato"},
    {"question":"A fragment of a theme that forms a melodic-rhythmic unit is called a:",
    "ans1":"countermelody", "ans2":"movement", "ans3":"motive", "correctAns":"motive"},
    {"question":"A performance practice based on the concept of a singing leader imitated by a chorus of followers is called:",
    "ans1":"thematic development", "ans2":"call and response", "ans3":"ostinato", "correctAns":"call and response"},
    {"question":"Which form features a statement of an idea, a contrasting idea, then a repetition of the first idea?",
    "ans1":"binary", "ans2":"ternary", "ans3":"improvisation", "correctAns":"ternary"},
    {"question":"A principle of form that is based on repeated alterations of a given melody (but still recognizable) is called:",
    "ans1":"repetition", "ans2":"contrast", "ans3":"variation", "correctAns":"variation"},
    {"question":"Which dynamic marking would indicate to the performer to play gradually louder?",
    "ans1":"sforzando", "ans2":"diminuendo", "ans3":"crescendo", "correctAns":"crescendo"},
    {"question":"Which of the following would indicate a fast tempo?",
    "ans1":"vivace", "ans2":"grave", "ans3":"andante", "correctAns":"vivace"},
    {"question":"Tempo refers to:", "ans1":"the time signature", "ans2":"the rate of speed", 
        "ans3":"the volume level", "correctAns":"the rate of speed"},
    {"question":"A musical sound is perceived at a certain volume, which is referred to as the:",
    "ans1":"frequency", "ans2":"dynamics", "ans3":"tempo", "correctAns":"dynamics"},
    {"question":"Which term indicates that a piece should be performed very loudly?",
    "ans1":"mezzo forte", "ans2":"fortissimo", "ans3":"presto", "correctAns":"fortissimo"},
    {"question":"If a composer wants to indicate despair in a piece of music, which of the following tempos would be appropriate?",
    "ans1":"grave", "ans2":"pianissimo", "ans3":"allegro", "correctAns":"grave"},
    {"question":"Returning to the original tempo after a change in the music is best indicated by what marking in the score?",
    "ans1":"a tempo", "ans2":"accelerando", "ans3":"non troppo", "correctAns":"a tempo"},
    {"question":"If a composer wants to indicate excitement in a piece of music, which of the following tempos would be appropriate?",
    "ans1":"forte", "ans2":"presto", "ans3":"adagio", "correctAns":"presto"},
    {"question":"Gradually getting softer in music is best indicated by which term in the score?",
    "ans1":"ritardando", "ans2":"crescendo", "ans3":"diminuendo"},
    {"question":"If the music is gradually speeding up, the term used to describe this is:",
    "ans1":"accelerando", "ans2":"diminuendo", "ans3":"a tempo", "correctAns":"accelerando"}
]